okay now what I want to talk about is
the science shutdown and I'm very
alarmed about the science shutdown
because I view this as not very
scientific and in fact what would we do
in a scientific situation if we were
trying to understand where we were one
thing we would do is we would run
controlled experiments and I want to
want to take I want to take the
opportunity to talk about Daniel shaver
and Tony timppa who were both killed by
police on video
Daniel shaver was in a motel I believe
that he was an exterminator who had some
kind of a or something like that had
been spotted by the police he was given
extremely complicated instructions as to
how to behave he could not follow the
directions I think he adjusted his belt
while he was being told to crawl on the
floor
and as a result he lost his life because
the instructions were not possible for
him to carry out with that error had
that happened to George Floyd my
question is would we if we reverse
George Floyd and Daniel shaver or an
even more accurate version would be this
Tony Tempah killing in Dallas which I
think happened in 2016 as well as Daniel
shaver my question is would we
unquestionably say that the Dallas
killing and the Arizona killing would
have been racially motivated had George
Floyd happened to have been interchanged
and would we be ignoring what happened
in Minneapolis that is what a scientist
does a scientist examines hypotheses and
questions and I just saw a notice go out
to the alumni of Cal Tech saying that we
had to eliminate anyone who still
resisted these measures to increase this
awareness of our terrible bigotry and
quite honestly the key problem that
we're facing here is is that we are all
for some reason terrified of telling the
black community you're wrong the black
community that is behind black lives
matter is frequently wrong and the idea
that we can't talk to people as equals
and tell them when they're wrong
and explain and run controlled tests and
try to talk about inference patterns
when we know that there's prejudice in
the system we know that there's police
brutality but they make terrible
arguments one of the arguments is that
no white people are afraid of the police
and that only black people can
understand what it means to be afraid of
police can you possibly imagine that
that's true after watching the Daniel
shaver and Tony timppa video no you
can't so what do we have today
we have an unusual situation we have
science magazine and nature for example
who've signed on nature runs a picture
that says black lives matter that's not
saying that black lives actually matter
which is obvious and doesn't require
comment it's saying black lives matter
both the organization and the point all
right so that's what we would call an
overloaded statement in computer science
right it means more than one thing at
the same time so now science and nature
are behind this and now what we have
right is is that if you contradict this
then it must mean that you don't think
black lives matter well that's not how
science works and that's why we have
terms like overloaded where one thing
means multiple things and that's why we
have controlled trials and what you have
today is a beautiful example where you
have something where all of us care
about a murder of a man in broad
daylight even if he was a convicted
felon and not particularly a good person
who did not necessarily see black lives
as mattering because he may have engaged
in violence towards black people but we
all care and we all we all you know our
black people matter to us just as our
white people and our Asian people and
our Native American people and there are
people who are more screwed over than
even many black people it's enough it's
incredibly important that everybody in a
free society be able to interact as
equals and when when Jews are wrong you
have to be able to say hey Jews you're
wrong when whites are wrong when women
are wrong we have to be able to say
women are wrong this idea that this is
it this concept of I am more oppressed
therefore I am more correct and my lived
experience is not understandable by any
other person other than me
have to tech tackle this bolt ball
head-on there is nothing I want less
than to tell the least advantaged person
a person sold into slavery as a child
sexual slavery crippled a person who is
known only deprivation I don't want to
have to tell that person you're wrong
but if that person says that 2 times 3
equals a chicken that person is wrong I
don't care how trans they are we have to
have the ability inside of a free
society to treat each other reverently
as equals and part of being an equal is
you're wrong if I can't tell you you're
wrong you're not my equal and I
absolutely believe that you're wrong and
I think that you're my equal and so I'm
going to tell you
science magazine you're out of control
our universities are out of control
our leaders are out of control there
should at a minimum be a large number of
people who spent the day researching
because they don't understand exactly
how we came to this position I spent the
day partially researching not to make a
point of it but I wasn't gonna stop it
and by the way I have lost relatives who
I loved and I have spent less time
grieving them the way people are
pretending to grieve over George Floyd
it's a tragic situation but you didn't
know him what was terrible wasn't George
Floyd's death in particular it was the
murderous cop behavior and the murderous
cop behavior is white on white it's
white on black it's black on white it
happens all over the spectrum and what
I've said before and I just said it on
Bret and Heather's Dark Horse podcast
which I recommend you check out is that
there's a scene in Animal House and I
want you to look at it where there's a
parade and there's a marching band and
the marching band has to follow the guy
with the baton and somebody knocks the
guy who's got the baton out of the way
and starts picking up the baton and
taking the marching band down an alley
we were all in a situation where we were
pissed off because of coke ovid we had
unemployment spiking people have been
dissatisfied across the board and black
lives matter took the baton because of
this incredible situation with this vile
murder I mean I assume it's murder I
don't know what he died of but I'm my
assumption is that it's murder and the
in Animal House when when the barchi
ban goes down the alley that was all of
us we were all upset about all sorts of
things and now we've got one group
pretending that they are in control of
everything that's going on and in fact
the world is really upset and the
realist in the world is upset I was
talking about for years you guys are all
bored I've called it the N squared
revolution look it up on the portal
clips channel subscribe there I mean
this is absolutely preposterous and okay
so we've lost science we've lost nature
we've lost the independence of the
Academy everybody's frightened that
they're gonna get Hall called a bigot
and quite honestly the people we want in
science are the people who aren't
frightened the people who have the
courage to stand alone the people who
resist groupthink group feel the people
who are overthinking it because that's
what we do in science we think we don't
feel our way through things that's why
it's a counterweight if you want
feelings by all means go watch a soap
opera but this is science and this is
not scientific and quite frankly what we
are doing is performative it's silly and
I'm gonna drop the biggest issue of all
the science establishment fights to make
sure that it doesn't have to take
extraordinary measures to bring blacks
women and other minorities into science
by using our immigration system and
they've studied this internally at the
National Science Foundation originally
in the policy research and analysis
division under Eric Bloch and Peter
house in the mid-1980s okay do you
understand what I'm saying if you want
to get women and minorities and
everybody else into science here's what
you do you allow the labor market to
work without using visas as labor relief
you start classifying the workers who
are in the labs as workers and not
calling them students or post doctoral
students and I've written it up this up
in a paper called how and why government
University and Industry create labor
shortages this is an entire sham and if
you if those people care so deeply about
black lives mattering and get about
getting black people in the stem here's
what you do you take the peep you
reinstitute mandatory report retirement
for people who've been in their job for
20 years with very little pro
activity okay and then you cut off the
supply of visas so that you can't pay
for work by giving people immigration
and you're forced to use the labor
market and then you stop talking about
how beautiful it is that science is
international not because it isn't
international but because that is a
cover story so there's a ton to do and
I'm willing to do it and if you want to
really talk about how to bring black
lives into science it would be my
pleasure so if you want to come after me
and call me a bigot I would be so happy
to take the National Science Foundation
and the National Academy of Sciences on
one hell of a Nantucket sleigh ride to
point out that they have studied
internally how it is that women and
minorities come in to science and that
they sought to fake a labor shortage in
order to get relief so that it didn't
have to happen so if you want to come
after me
Caltech if you want to come after me
National Science Foundation if you want
to tell me what a bigot I am for doing
partial differential equations on a day
that I'm supposed to put my pen down for
my reverence for my black brothers and
sisters know I care about my black
brothers and sisters one hell of a lot
more than you do because I've been at
this since the 1980s and if you read my
papers and you read my work you will see
that it has been consistent it's not one
day it's a lifetime commitment and I've
said something else to you okay and that
is this the soul of American science is
the middle finger so consider this
National Science Foundation science
magazine nature magazine as a challenge
my middle fingers pointed straight at
you you're weak you're cowardly you
don't deserve to be in charge of science
you've jumped the shark you don't know
what you're doing and if you want to
talk about how to get blacks into
science I'm absolutely your guy come
after me understood thank you love you
guys